Inventory of Leslie Gottesman papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Printed Matter, 1935-2007
  - National Geographic, "With the Italians in Eritrea," "Region in Rebellion: Eritrea," "A Little Humanity Amid the Horrors of War,", 1935-1986 (Box-folder 11: 20)
  - National Union of Eritrean Students (NUES), 1980-1983 (Box-folder 11: 21)
  - National Union of Eritrean Students in North America (NUESNA), undated (Box-folder 11: 22)
  - National Union of Eritrean Women (NUEWn), 1980-1993 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - New Internationalist, 2004 (Box-folder 12: 2)
  - News items and newspaper clippings. Eritrea, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 12: 3)
  - News items and newspaper clippings. Eritrea, 1983-2007 (Box-folder 12: 4)
  - News items and newspaper clippings. Ethiopia, 1983-1994 (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - Press and Information Department, "Ethiopia: General Information," "Eritrea: Then and Now,", 1958-1976 (Box-folder 12: 6)
  - Provisional Government of Eritrea, undated (Box-folder 12: 7)
  - Red Sea Press, undated (Box-folder 12: 8)
  - Relief Society of Tigray (REST), undated (Box-folder 12: 9)
  - Reporters Without Borders (Reporters Sans Frontieres) (RSF), protest letter, Eritrea Annual Report, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 12: 10)
  - "A Short History of Memher Teweldemedhin," "A Short Biography of Isahak Teweldemedhin: War on Illiteracy,", 1986 (Box-folder 12: 11)
  - Santa Cruz Friends of Eritrea, 1990 (Box-folder 12: 12)
  - The State of Eritrea Ministry of Finance, Cultural Heritage Project, "On the Need to Preserve Eritrean Oral History and Literature,", 2000 (Box-folder 12: 13)
  - Tigray Peoples' Liberation Front (TPLF), 1983-1984 (Box-folder 12: 14)
  - Tourism, Eritrea, 1994-2000 (Box-folder 12: 15)
  - Union of Tigreans in Europe Women's Study Group, "Women of Tigray in Struggle,", 1981 (Box-folder 12: 16)
  - Union of Tigreans in North America (UTNA), 1982 (Box-folder 12: 17)
  - Unitarian Universalist Service Committee, undated (Box-folder 12: 18)
  - United Nations Association (UNA), undated (Box-folder 12: 19)
  - United Nations Development Program (UNDP), undated (Box-folder 12: 20)
  - United States Committee for a Free Eritrea, undated (Box-folder 12: 21)
  - University Research Expeditions Program (University of California, Berkeley), undated (Box-folder 12: 22)
  - War on Want, "The Hidden Revolution," by Firebrace, James and Gayle Smith, 1982 (Box-folder 12: 23)
  - World Affairs Council of Northern California, 1992 (Box-folder 12: 24)
- Photographs, undated
  - Slides I, 1993 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - Slides II, Eritrea, 1993 (Box-folder 13: 2)
- Sound Recordings, 1993-2004 (Box 14-16)
  Note
  On compact sound cassettes.
  - Ali, Abdallah Mohammed and Mohammed, Abdulkander Saleh, April 29, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Almedon, Mesghenna, May 21, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Bahre, Abraham, April 2, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Bahre, Abraham, repeated by Paul, January 21, 1994 (Box 14)
  - Bahre, Abraham (tapes 1-2), September 9, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Bissirat, Gebremicael, May 4, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Blueford, Joyce, and Oscar Rosenblum (tapes 1-2), December 20, 2002 (Box 14)
  - Connell, Dan (tapes 1-2), March 25, 1992 (Box 14)
  - Connell, Dan, EPLF Club, Oakland, July 31, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Connell, Dan, on Africa Today, KPFA, March 29, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Demoz, Berhane, March 17, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Education and Human Resource Development, ESA Asmara, July 2001 (Box 14)
  - Education and Development, ESA Asmara, July 2001 (Box 14)
  - Eritrea Report back by Les, June 10, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Ephrem, Immouna, April 25, 1999 (Box 14)
  - Eyob, Salome, April 26, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Fre, Kibreab, April 12, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Gebrekristos, Temesgen, March 29, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Gebreyesus, Elsa, April 14, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Gerahtu, Tesfamichael, April 2, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Ghebreab, Yemane, April 29, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Ghebrai, Illen, April 18, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Ghebre, Ghiday, April 20, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Ghermai, Rahwa T., April 9, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Ghebremariam, Solomon, April 19, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Ghebreselassie, Beraki, April 21, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Ghebretensaie, Weldemichael, March 3, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Ghebretensaie, Weldemichael, April 3, 1993
  - Habtai, Araya, March 21, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Habtemariam, Mebrahtom, March 19, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Habtemariam, Mebrahtom, May 6, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Haile, Girmay, April 28, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Haile, Kaleb, March 15, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Hailemariam, Chefena, May 2, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Hailemariam, Petros, May 7, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Highfield, Paul, March 2, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Highfield, Paul, January 18, 1994 (Box 14)
  - Highfield, Paul (tapes 1-4), January 18, 1994 (Box 15)
  - Independence celebration evening, April 27, 1993 (Box 15)
  - Iyob, Meheret, March 13, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Iyob, Selome, March 17, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Jassir, Mohammedin, April 8, 1994 (Box 15)
  - Jones, Scott, May 6, 1992 (Box 15)
  - Jones, Scott, June 14, 1992 (Box 15)
  - Jones, Scott, September 1, 1992 (Box 15)
  - Kahsai, Asfaha, March 22, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Kahsai, Asfaha, April 10, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Kessler, Wayne and Laurie, March 4, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Kibreab, Estifanos, April 19, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Lijam, Senait, April 14, 1993 (Box 15)
  - Mahmud, Saleh, April 10, 1993 (Box 15)
  - Mahmud, Saleh, March 8, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Marcos, Joe, March 10, 1993 (Box 15)
  - Marcos, Joe, April 20, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Mehari, Asfaha, April 24, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Mekonnen, Yemane, March 31, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Meky, Saleh, April 20, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Melles, Ghebrehiwet, Apri 26, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Mesfin, Yirgalem, April 17, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Mesfun, Alula, March 7, 1993 (Box 15)
  - Mesfun, Yonas, April 16, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Mesghinna, Wolde, November 23, 1991 (Box 15)
  - Mohammed, Halima and Tedros Sium, April 12, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Negassi, Leteyesus and Senait Lijam, Apri l12, 1993 (Box 15)
  - Nur, Taha Mohammed, May 5, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Pateman, Roy and Nunu Kidane (tapes 1-2), May 5, 1993 (Box 15)
  - Pro-independence rally, Medefera, April 19, 1993 (Box 15)
  - PFOC presentation on Eritrea, June 13, 1993 (Box 15)
  - Referendum, first day, April, 1993 (Box 15)
  - Referendum celebration, April 1993 (Box 15)
  - Rich, Tessa and Yemane Tewolde, April 30, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Said, Mohammed Nur, April 30, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Shannon, Jeff and Robbie Marks, March 10, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Sium, Tedros, March 5, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Sium, Tedros, March 21, 2001 (Box 16)
  - Solomon, Semere, April 1, 1993 (Box 16)
  - Suleman, Ali, June 2, 2002 (Box 16)
  - Teckie, Amaniel, March 29, 2001 (Box 16)
  - Tecle, Amanuel, July 12, 1991 (Box 16)
  - Tedros, Zecarias, April 17, 2001 (Box 16)
  - Tedros, Zecarias, and Keflemariam Zerom, April 7-8, 1993 (Box 16)
  - Teklay, Robel, April 9, 2001 (Box 16)
  - Temesgen, Hertema, April 26, 2001 (Box 16)
  - Tesfai, Secretary of Agriculture, April 21, 1993 (Box 16)
  - Tesfagiorgios, Abeba, April 9, 1993 (Box 16)
  - Tesfamariam, Issayas, June 14, 1992 (Box 16)
  - Tewelde, Yacob, March 15, 1993 (Box 16)
  - Thomas, Sister (tape 1-2), March 16, 1993 (Box 16)
  - "The Liberation Struggle," ESA panel, Asmara, July 2001 (Box 16)
  - UNA presentation on Eritrea, July 25, 1993 (Box 16)
  - Ugubeab, Paulos, April 6, 2001 (Box 16)
  - Woldemichael, Solomon, March 21, 1993 (Box 16)
  - Woldesillasie, Kidane, April 25, 2001 (Box 16)
  - Zerom, Kiflemariam, March 19, 1993 (Box 16)
  - Zerom, Kiflemariam, April 30, 2001 (Box 16)
- Videorecordings, 1993
  On VHS video cassettes.
  - Massawa and Asmara, April 1993 (Box 16)
  - "Zecarias Tedros Shows and Talks About His Art,", April 17, 1993 (Box 16)
  - Zecarias Tedros, art, April 17, 1993 (Box 16)
  - Selection from Eritrea, Frankie Duhl, April 1993 (Box 16)